Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to update our enemy a bit.
Currently, right now, if I hit my enemy, it will just play damage animation and that's all We're
going to make it so that whenever we have our enemy, our enemy will be launched back in the direction
that we hit it.
And if, for example, I hit my enemy from behind, the enemy will turn around and face me.
So in order to set that up, if we head back to our player blueprint and go to Earth as applied damage,
we just want to drag off damage closer and type in self.
So the reason we're doing this, if we go back to our sand and beep and go to our event, any damage,
we can now reference the damage which damages our Scampton.
So we're going to get the location of our damage closer and the location of our Scampton, and then
we'll use that information to determine where our Scampton should face.
So if we just drag off damage closer and look forward, get actor location.
Ben, if we just right click and we'll get actor location and track up here and forget unit director
plug in here to two.
So we're going to be getting the unit direction of our damage closer to our ask antennas.
And we just want to right click it and split the structure and we're only concerned with the value in
the x axis.
I want us to just right click and look for print string so you can visually see something.
Look up X into here.
And focus up into health and this into here.
Now, if I go compile and I go play.
If I hit my enemy from behind, it's going to print shrink a positive value.
If I hit my enemy from behind, then it's going to print shrink a negative value.
So you can see it was minus one.
And like in front of it I hit it will be one.
Using this.
We're going to update our enemies movement direction whenever we have them.
So what of this return value x If we just drag up here and look for less than if this value is ever
less than one?
That means we are currently in front of the enemy and we want our enemy to continue facing us.
So if I go back here and just drag up here and look for select.
So if this is true, we're just on the right level on this value and change the pen type to be a float.
And we want this to have a true value of one.
If its value is ever greater than zero.
That means we're currently behind the enemy.
The enemy to turn around.
So if this condition is false, we want this to have a value of minus one.
Then we just want to delete this print string and I'm going to delete the notes here.
And we're just going to update our enemies movement direction.
So we just drag this in here and set it and hook this up here.
I'm going to collect these notes here and I'm just going to move everything back a bit.
And to make it cleaner, I'm going to drag in my house and look for less than or equal and hook us up
here.
So now we go compile and go play.
If I hit my enemy from here, it should turn around and face me so we can see the enemy down around
me.
I'm just going to jump over them.
Hit them.
They'll turn around and face me.
If I hit them from this direction.
They should continue staying where they are and try and face me.
Nice.
The next thing we're going to do is make it so that whenever we hit our enemy and it still has help,
we're going to launch our enemy back in the direction that we hit them.
So false.
I want you to just drag up here and look for a launch character.
Just check.
X, Y, and Z, Right.
So that we replace our characters velocity with the values here and right click here and look for split
structure.
PIN in Z have a value of something like 150 and in X basically going to use the value here and just
multiply it by a negative number so that we launch our enemy in the opposite direction of where it was.
Here someone put a value of -800.
And hook us up to x.
Now if I click compile, close this and go play and I hit my enemy, they'll be launched back in the
opposite direction.
Although, as you can see, this kind of breaks.
One of the systems that we made earlier.
When I hit my enemy, it will no longer turn around and face me.
And that is because if I just go back to my skin improvement.
Earlier we made this blueprint which says detect if the content is on the edge of the world.
When we launch our enemy up in the air, this variable becomes false.
So then it triggers this and makes my enemy move it in the opposite direction just so you can see what
I mean.
I'm going to turn this on for full duration to compile and close this.
So I go play and I hit my enemy.
It's kind of hard to see.
So I'm going to actually launch my enemy in the air a bit more.
Something like 300.
And I'm going to expand my map so he doesn't fall off.
If I go play, I lost my enemy.
We can see that it becomes false because the line trace isn't hang anything.
So make my enemy move in the opposite direction.
In order to fix this, whenever my enemy is damaged, we're going to set a boolean variable to be true.
So create a new variable and call it enemy damaged.
And whenever our enemy is damaged, we're going to set this trouble to be true.
Took this up here.
And then after this, you won't have a variable delay.
So the way a variable delay will work is it kind of works the same as a normal delay.
However, if this node is called again, then it will stop the retrievable delay.
So we won't have a value of one.
And after one second we will tell the game that we should set the enemy damage variable to be false.
Then on here on handle movement, we're only going to handle our movement if our enemy is not dead or.
Enemy is not damaged.
Or if our enemy is not falling.
So if we just react in character movement and fall is falling.
And look this up here.
So now if I go compile and go play, I'm just going to remove that line trace.
To compile.
So now I go play and I hit my enemy.
I'll be launched up in the air and then face me if I hit it from this direction.
We lost away, but I'll still try and face me.
I can jump over them.
At the end, we'll be locked away and then try and face me.
So with this, we just polish up our enemy a bit, so it's a bit more satisfying when we hit and damage
our enemy.
I also gave my enemy a bit more help.
That's why I was not tired after three hits.
One more thing, because when I launched my Scampton, I noticed them back in the air and they launched
quite far.
This was make sure to apply some friction to them when they're in the air.
So under character movement in details, look for lateral friction and just put a value here.
I'm going to put 2.5, so there's a bit of friction when they're falling through the air, so they're
going to play.
Hit them.
They're not launched as far back, and I think that's a bit better.
You can play around with the values that you want to launch them back and the lateral friction, but
I'm going to leave mine at those values.